how did it happen that our countries are
как так получилось что наши страны
at war? Well, because you, uh, didn’t accept
воюют Ну потому что вы э-э не приняли
Russia as your state, in the sense that you didn’t
Россию как своё государство в смысле не
accept Russia as your state.
приняли России как своё государство У
I don’t even have that in Bingo. What does this
меня даже такого нету в Бинго Что это
mean? Well, the fact is that we need to live together with Russia
означает А ну то что надо жить с Россией
and we need to  its composition will enter and you will
дружно и надо в состав её войти и будете
And there will be peace in the whole
И будет мир во всём
world
мире Здравствуйте
Hello Hello listen Why do you think
Здравствуйте слушайте Как вы считаете
our countries
почему наши страны
are at war Well because
воюют Ну потому
because no
что потому что мозгов нету у
one has brains Well our countries Well how can countries not
кого Ну у наших стран Ну как у стран не
have the brains of a country  - these are
может быть мозгов страны - это
political formations, these are not people,
политические образование это же не люди
but I mean, there is a collective brain,
но В смысле есть же коллективный мозг
yes, you
как бы да
can say it like that. You just
можно так сказать это Вы только что
came up with a collective brain.
придумали коллективный мозг Да в смысле
Yes, I mean, how can I explain this? Well,
в смысле как бы это объяснить Да ну вот
the country is moving in some
страна движется каким-то
way And the majority supports this
путём И большинство поддерживает вот
this path if they didn’t support the
этот путь если бы они не поддерживали
country wouldn’t go this way
страна бы не шла этим путём
knives says like Why did your
ножи говорит типа Почему Ваш
collective mind attack our
коллективный разум напал на наш
collective
коллективный
mind Well,
разум Ну потому
because well, your collective mind
что ну у вашего коллективного разума
has no brain at all Yes, I understand, yes And
мозг отсутствует напрочь Да понял да А
you Yes, that’s what your brain collective
вы Да вот что ваш мозговий коллективный
mind is  That's why he attacked
разум Вот почему он напал на
us How why Because you gathered in
нас Как почему Потому что вы собрались в
NATO So what, well, you would have gathered in NATO
НАТО Так и что ну и собрались бы в НАТО
and what to urgently take back Crimea So
и что забрать срочно Крым Вот и
start a full-fledged war, if we
развязать полноценную войну если бы мы е
hadn't started the war, the war would have gone to ours on
не развязали то война ушла бы на наш на
on naturally moved it  to your Terry
на естественно перенесли её на ваш Терри
Ponia That is, you attacked Ukraine to
Поня То есть вы напали на Украину чтобы
protect yourself from
защититься от
NATO, including the understanding. How do you
НАТО в том числе понял А как вы
assess the fact that now NATO is
оцениваете то что сейчас НАТО к заднему
approaching your anus from Finland,
проходу вашему подбирается с Финляндии
for example from the
например с
Baltics? Well, this is our next  We’ll end the problem
балтии Ну это следующая наша проблема мы
with Ukraine and we’ll solve it with
сес Украиной закончим а будем решать а с
Kazakhstan. What will you
Казахстаном Что будете
do with Kazakhstan? You don’t need to
делать с Казахстаном ничего не надо
do anything. They learn from other people’s mistakes,
делать Они они на чужих ошибках учатся
that’s why. Well, I heard that in Kazakhstan they
поэтому Ну там я слыл что в Казахстане
don’t really like
типа там тоже не совсем любят
Russians either. How many people
русских Какое количество туда
have fallen there?
свалилось
-it was
я сы что там кого-то
recognized by the Armed Forces as normal. They are just playing a
призна ВС нормально Они просто ведут
double game.
двойную игру
Well, how and when will this
хорошо чем и когда закончится эта
war end? Well, today I watched a lot of
война Ну сегодня я смотрел много
analysts. Well, everyone is inclined to believe that
аналитиков Ну все склоняются к тому что
this
в этом
year it has been proven, maybe he
годуя доказана может прово
realized that he won’t pull it off.  about So and what do
понял что он не потянет про Так и что
analysts say when when the end and
говорят аналитики то когда когда конец и
in what form 54 country but in the fall
в какой форме 54 страной но осенью
most likely there will be some
скорее всего будут какие-нибудь
attempts to reach an agreement they will bargain for
попытки договориться будут торговаться
some time And what can Putin
какое-то вре А о чём О чём Путин может
bargain about that he will give up Kherson or that
торговаться что он Херсон отдаст или что
he is in the Constitution and  what can Putin
он в Конституции а чём может Путин
negotiate? He won’t give up
договариваться Он же не будет отдавать
Kherson to Zaporozhye, well, the first thing is the
Херсон Запорожье что ну Первое это
neutral status
нейтральный статус
of those agreements when you left the
к тем договорн когда вы выходили из
Soviet Union, it was
состава Советского Союза там было
agreed upon and the neutral State where it
оговорено да нейтральный Шта где это
was
было
agreed upon. Well  this is the treaty Yes, when there
оговорено Ну вот этот договор Да когда
was no treaty there was
никакого не было договора там было
stipulated no treaty what kind of
оговорено никакого договора какой вообще
treaty came out of the USSR by the act of
договор вышли из состава ССР актом
declaring
провозглашения
Independence neutrals there was
Независимости нейтрали не не было
no declaration of neutrality
никакой декларации о нейтралитете
declaration declaration now I remember
декларация декларация сейчас я вспомню
what it was called When you, well, there
как она называлось Когда вы ну там у нас
was a coup there Yes  State Emergency Committee, yes State
же переворот произошёл Да гкчп вот да
Emergency Committee and a couple of days later we announced the
гкчп и у нас через пару дней объявили
act of proclamation of Independence Yes,
акт провозглашения Независимости Да
independence Yes, there is nothing about a
независимость Да там ничего слова про
neutral status No, I can
нейтральный статус Нет я могу сейчас
read it now and there is no,
прочитать и есть есть нет
look now I’m reading it straight  let's
смотритесь сейчас читаю прямо давай
read the act of proclamation of independence
читай вот акт проголошення незалеж
with the fact that dadada, here I am for you. Look,
уя с тем что дадада вот я тебе Смотри
I will immediately translate it into Russian for you
вот я тебе на русский сразу буду
because here is the act of
переводить потому что вот акт
declaring the independence of Ukraine
провозглашения независимости Украины
based on the mortal danger that
исходя из смертельной опасности которая
loomed over Ukraine in connection with the
нависла над Украиной в связи с
coup d'etat in the USSR on
государственным переворотом в СССР 19
August 19, ninety-one
августа девяносто первого года
continues the thousand-year tradition of the
продолжает тысячелетнюю традицию
state of education in Ukraine based
государства образования в Украине исходя
on the right to
из права на
self-determination, according to the UN statute and
самоопределение думат статутом ООН и
other international legal
другими международно правовыми
documents from the gums, in
документами с десн как
short, fulfilling the declaration of the
короче исполняя декларацию
state sovereignty of Ukraine, the
государственный суверенитет Украины
Verkhovna Rada of the Ukrainian Radian
Верховная Рада украинской радянской
Socialist Republic urochisto this
Социалистической Республики урочисто это
festively proclaims the independence of
празднично провозглашает независимость
Ukraine and the creation of an independent
Украины и создание самостоятельной
Ukrainian state of Ukraine, the territory of
украинской державы Украины территория
Ukraine is indivisible and
Украины есть неделимой и
inviolable, from now on on the territory of
неприкосновенно отныне на территории
Ukraine they have a purity like this
Украины имеют чисть типа как это
in Russian, in short, the activity is
по-русски короче активность
exclusively of the Constitution  and the laws of
исключительно Конституции и законы
Ukraine, this act is gaining decorous
Украины этот акт набирает чинно
reality from the moment it is
действительности с момента его
captured, everything is nothing here  about non-bloc
схвати всё ничего тут про внеблоковый
status and so on.
статус и так Дальше
Then there’s no Well, I’ll check this point later,
нету Ну я потом проверю вот этот момент
well, there was an agreement, look,
ну есть были договорн смотрите
an agreement is when we
договорённость - это когда мы с кем-то
come to an agreement with someone And so on Yes, there’s no
договариваемся И так дальше Да никаких
document What kind of document are you and I
до есть документ Какой документ что мы с
signing? No,
вами ето подписываем нету такого
nothing to do with when  Crimea, in the same
не причём когда Крым он же этими же
words, exactly in connection with the fact that
словами ровно в связи с тем что в
look, look, the point is that
т смотри смотри дело дело в том что
look, in the Soviet Union, the USSR
смотри в этом в Советском Союзе урср
was the founding state of the Soviet
было государство основатель Советского
Union and it had  the right to secede
Союза и оно имело право на выход
According to the union treaty, you know
Согласно союзного договора Ты же знаешь
in 22M when the Soviet Union was founded
в 22М году когда основали Советский Союз
Yes, Ukraine Belarus Russia
Да подписали там Украина Беларусь Россия
also signed there Yes, the right to secede was clearly stated there
ещё Да вот там было чётко прописано
in the Constitution of the Soviet
право выхода в Конституции Советского
Union there was a right to secede and the Ukrainian RSR
Союза было право выхода и украинская РСР
implemented it Yes Crimea never and no
реализовала его Да Крым э никогда и ни
others
другие
subjects of Ukraine Yes, they didn’t have the right to
субъекты Украины Да они не имели право
secede like that. They didn’t have, let’s say, they didn’t
выхода так Они не имели скажем они не
create Ukraine as a union
создавали Украину как союзное
state
государство
and they couldn’t secede from it, so the
а и не могли из него выйти поэтому
analogy is absolutely not the same,
абсолютно аналогия не такая
you see They they They are these  words that
видишь Они они Они вот этими словами что
you wrote there Due to the fact that there
вы там написали В связи с тем что
was a coup d'état,
произошёл государственный переворот
there is an impending threat, I don’t
нависшая угроза напас пофиг что они
care what they wrote, I don’t care what they wrote
смотри пофиг что они писали
at all, what they wrote there. In short, the
вообще что они там писали Это короче уже
stage has already been passed, everyone
пройденный этап ти все
understands everyone is bombing Crimea and everyone agrees
понимают все бомбят Крым и все согласны
America says Crimea is Ukraine and
Америка говорит Крым - это Украина и
Crimea Sevastopol is all and 20 will pass and
Крым Севастополь это все и 20 пройдёт и
50, yes, that is, look here, yes, that
50 да то есть смотри тут такое да то
is, America, the whole world recognizes Crimea as
есть Америка весь мир признаёт Крым
Ukrainian  moreover, Belgorod recognizes
украинский больше того Белгород признаёт
Ukrainian because they allow
украинский потому что разрешают
American weapons Belgorod means they
американским оружием Белгород значит
recognize Belgorod - this is
признают Белгород - это
Ukraine Putin recognizes Belgorod as Ukraine
Украина Путин признаёт Белгород Украиной
Because if he recognized this as
Потому что если бы он признавал это
the territory of the Russian Federation, he would
территории Российской Федерации он бы
somehow answer why Putin does not respond
как-то ответил почему Путин не отвечает
to shelling of
на обстрелы
Belgorod Hello, he
Белгорода Здравствуйте он вам все
doesn’t have all the power plants for you  so power plants are already being
электростанции нет так электростанции и
bombed, and last year they were bombed and the
так бомбит и прошлый год бомбили и
year before that, well, look, here in
позапрошлый это ж а как смотри Вот в
Belgrade, look in Belgorod  girl and
Белграде смотри в Белгороде девочка да
boy peaceful people are dying in Belgrade
мальчик мирные люди погибают в Белграде
why Putin can’t protect and that means
почему Путин не может защитить и значит
Belgrade is Ukraine Ukraine’s right to hit
Белград - это Украина право Украины бить
Belgorod Well, you’re directly drawing conclusions Yes,
Белгороду Ну ты прямо выводы делаешь Да
brilliant, really Well, look, if
гениальны ну реально Ну смотри если
Belgorod is Russia then Putin should
Белгород - это Россия тогда Путин должен
somehow react and do  so
как-то взять отреагировать и сделать так
that Belgorod doesn’t fire, that’s what he
чтобы Белгород не обстреливал так он
does How Well, he’s moving in a hundred
делает Как Ну движется в сто
American where he’s
американским куда он
moving towards Kharkov where he’s
движется в сторону Харькова где он там
moving there moving moving
движется движется движе
low where well where Let’s so how many
невысокой где ну где Давай так сколько
centimeters in  the day
сантиметров в день
is moving Well, 17 from 17 cm a
продвигается Ну 17 с 17 см в
day, so a
день так вот а
Putin is moving 17 cm a
а Путин продвигается на 17 см в
day in Kadyrov by 17 Dude, in short, you
день в Кадырова на 17 Чувак ты короче
really lifted my spirits
реально
Yes, Putin is moving 17 cm a day towards
Да Путин движется на 17 см в день к
Kharkov That was great Hello, I’m
Харькову Здоровеньки было Здравствуйте я
from the city of Khmelnitsky Where are you from?  I'm from
из города Хмельницкий Вы откуда я с
Krasnoyarsk And what do you communicate?
Красноярска А чем общаетесь
Well, in the sense that I communicate I communicate What do
Ну в смысле что общаюсь общаюсь О чём
you communicate about what What about life about life about
общаетесь об чём О чём о жизни о жизни о
life Okay, a question for you, how is it
жизни Хорошо вопросик вам как так да
possible, yes, a blog, I’m a blogger, how did you get it? You’re
блог я блогер как получи ты сейчас это
filming it now, yes, I
снимаешь всё да сейчас
’m filming it now. Well, let’s film it. I understand.
снимаю Ну давай снимай Понял
The question is, how did it happen that our
Вопрос как так получилось что наши
countries are
страны
at war? Well, because
воюют Ну потому что
you didn’t accept Russia as your
вы не приняли Россию как своё
state, in the sense that you didn’t accept Russia
государство в смысле не приняли Россию
as your state.  I do
как своё государство У меня даже такого
n’t even have that in Bingo What does this
нету в Бинго Что это
mean? Well, that we need to live together with Russia
означает Ну то что надо жить с Россией
and we need to join it and you will
дружно и надо в состав её войти и будете
And there will be peace in the whole world. Cool
И будет мир во всём мире Прикольно А
Why should we go, for example, we want to
зачем нам ходить например вот мы хотим
join  some rich country,
войти в состав какой-то богатой страны
yes And I’m looking at you, you’re from Russia,
да А я вот смотрю на вас вы из России у
you have such squalor there. I don’t want to live
вас такое убожество там Я не хочу жить
like you, I don’t want to be like
так как вы я не хочу вот быть таким как
And who A And who said that we have squalor,
А кто А А кто сказал что у нас убожество
I see Well, show me the cart, wait  yes, it’s me
я вижу Ну покажите воз погоди да это я
at the dacha, just in a temporary hut, and damn it’s
на даче просто Во времянке а все блин
all wretchedness, everyone at the dacha, show me,
все уко убожества все на даче покажи
wait, show me the bathhouse, I have bathhouse 6 on
погодите показать баню у меня баня 6 на
Show Wow, well, it’s night, so
по Покажи Ничего себе ну сечас ночь Ну и
what, show me if  real Come on,
что ну покажи если реально Давай так ты
so you're a blogger, you're filming this Well,
так ты блогер ты это снимаешь Ну так
show me personally I'm not filming right now, I'm
покажи мне лично я я сейчас не
not even filming Yaya What's the name
снимаю даже не снимаю Яя Как зовут
Andrey Andrey me Alexander Ale
Андрей Андрей меня Александр Але
unreal I've never seen
нереально Я никогда не видел
there is a Lich
есть Лич
bathhouse Every Russian has a bathhouse This is what
баня У каждого россиянина есть баня Вот
every Russian has  bathhouse
это у каждого россиянина есть баня У
I have a basement in my house, now I’m making a basement
меня дом цоколь вот сейчас цоколь делаю
like every Russian has a bathhouse, I don’t
как это у каждого россияне на бане я не
believe it. Well, how can this be? Are you really
верю Ну как это может быть Неужели вы
such a rich country that everyone has a bathhouse?
такая богатая страна что у каждого баня
So  I mean, we are a poor country, a rich country,
Так мы в смысле бедная страна богатая
I say How is it such a rich country that
говорю Как так богатая страна что у
everyone has a bathhouse, of course yes? Well, the
каждого баня у вас конечно да Ну у
Americans don’t have a bathhouse for everyone. You’re
американцев нету у каждого бани Ты
kidding me. What kind of bathhouse? Damn, the
прикалываешься Какая баня Блин так
Americans don’t know what a Russian
американцы не знают что такое русская
bathhouse is. Self-propelled guns. Listen, where do you get a bathhouse? You
баня САУ Слушай откуда у вас баня у вас
don’t have normal toilets  you
туалетов нету нормальных ты
're telling a fairy tale about the Bathhouse No, don't
рассказываешь сказку про Баню Нет не
push me, the bathhouse
загоняй мне баня тебе
told you it's good Show this Show the bathhouse that
сказал хорош Покажи эту Покажи баню что
it exists, I'm still building it, and that is, there's no
она есть я строю ещё её а то есть нету
bathhouse, but I'll understand  I
бани да пойм
'll show you in the process,
покажу она в процес
first there was a bathhouse now it's construction
сначала была баня теперь строительство
Well, at least show me Okay or is it being built
Ну хотя бы покажи Ладно или она строится
wait a minute Yes you or what Yes I what if you
погоди Да ты что ли Да я что если ты
say you have a bathhouse And now there is no
говоришь у тебя баня А теперь уже нет
bathhouse I told you I have a bathhouse
бани Я же тебе сказал у меня баня
construction in the
строительство в
bathhouse Second year first year  you're building a
бане Второй год первый год ты строишь
log house roof, it's been shrinking for a year, it's
сруб крышу она год даёт усадку вот год
been a year now,
прол сейчас идт
so I have lumber, yes And how many years does it
вот у меня пиломатериал да А сколько лет
take to build a bathhouse according to the technology?
по технологии баню надо строить
If you've been building for 2 years,
получается Если вы 2 года строите
it's already a year  shrinkage of the
уже год ты даёшь на усадку
log house,
сруба по
in fact, I don’t have any light here, turn on the
сути у меня тут света нету те включить
flashlight, yes, let’s turn on the flashlight, that’s
фонарик да Давай включи фонарик что та
such a rich country, there is no light in the bathhouse
такая богатая страна нет света в бане
setup, I’m building an aircraft at night, but it’s
настройке я ночью строю что ли ВС но там
already
уже
dark there during the day, it’s dark Yes, you’re
темно днём темно Да ты
like, where are you, where is the flashlight, even the flashlight
натуре Какие вы где фонарик даже фонарик
doesn’t turn on?
не включается
- I'm on the phone, you go ahead,
какие-то Я в телефоне ты давай так давай
without a flashlight, without a flashlight, just the camera.
без фонарика без фонарика просто камеру
Turn it over so that I can see the bathhouse, not at you
Переверни чтобы я видел баню не на тебя
so that it looks at the bathhouse, so in short,
чтобы она смотрела а на баню так короче
I'm
я
inside here  it’s dark Yes, I see you Ani ban,
внутри тут темно Да я тебя вижу Ани бан
don’t let me wait, wait, wait, now I’ll
ты не давай погоди погоди погоди сейчас
show you from afar Well, that’s what the
тебе покажу издалека Ну вот что фонарь
street lamp illuminates, I’ll show you
уличный освещает я тебе покажу
Yeah And how to switch the camera And I
Угу А как переключить камеру А во
found this, I have a bathhouse 6 ours so
нашёл вот вот это у меня баня 6 наше так
in the process How many people will be there
в проце Сколько сколько там людей будет
fit in this bathhouse a Pari
вмещать в эту баню а Пари
steam room e
парильни э
45 for 2 s to I tell people how many
45 на 2 с по Я говорю людей сколько
people can fit there for me people I build for myself Why do
людей мне людей я для себя строю А зачем
you need such a healthy one in short  steam room
вам такая здоровая короче парилка
because I’m about 2 meters tall and
а потому что я ростом э под 2 м и
therefore I need me to lie down and
поэтому мне надо чтобы я лёжа лёг и
enjoy normally Wait, lying down
нормально наслаждался Подождите лёжа лёг
you said She’s 4
вы сказали Она 4
meters long Well, there are two of you Can
м ну в длину Ну это вас два Может в
lie down long I have two I have a wife also, but I
лечь У меня два У меня жена есть ещё а
understand  you want you and then in length the wife
понял вы хотите вы и потом в длину жена
understood So next to it in width don’t listen
понял Так рядом это по ширине не слушай
but it’s good And where are you washing now if the
а хорошо А где же ты сейчас моешься если
Bathhouse is not ready for 2 years
Баня 2 года не
I have a shower cabin with a boiler
готова у меня душевая кабина с бойлером
Show me it’s real, I won’t go there,
Покажи реально она я туда не пойду
it means
значит
no, it’s not real, it’s real, at your dachas you
нету не реально реально есть на дачах вы
make showers with boilers, I’ve
делаете душевые кабины с бойлерам я тако
never seen that in my life,
в жизни не
but I mean, what do you mean to me?
видел а в смысле ты же ты что мне что ли
In our dachas, who makes a boiler in our dachas, they
У нас на дачах Кто у нас на даче бойлер
make something like this  uh, here in Siberia they
делает делают такую ээ у нас в Сибири
don’t do that here. Well, they make a
это у вас не делают Ну делают такое
bucket like this, the water is heated in it and then it
ведро нагревается в нём вода и потом
kind of flows out, what kind of pain does it have, that you have,
типа вытекает какой боли это у это у вас
I have an electric pain Yes, you have
у меня электрический боле Да ты у тебя
Sveta in the bathhouse  no, what kind of
Света в бане нет какой у тебя
electric boiler do you have, what are you inventing
электрический бойлер что ты выдумываешь
so it’s Sorry, the bathhouse is being built new Yes, you
так она Извини баня строится све Да ты в
didn’t install light in the bathhouse, but made an
баню не провёл свет а сделал
electric boiler, don’t tell the
электрический бойлер не рассказывай
fable, show that there is
басне покажи что есть
a boiler, ate You show that in Russia in
бойлер ели Ты покажи что бо России в
Russia, wait in Russia, initially you
России погоди в России изначально ты
buy a plot of land, build a toilet  then
покупаешь участок строишь туалет потом
you build a shower so I can show you show me
строишь душ чтобы я тебе покажи покажи
that there really is a boiler Show me that there
что бойлер реально есть Покажи что
really is a boiler in short you’re looking at me like
бойлер реально есть короче ты на меня да
what are some words  nye I
какой что что за слова какие-то ные Я же
communicate with you normally I don’t believe that
нормально с тобой общаюсь Я не верю что
at dachas there are boilers of the maximum type
на дачах есть бойлеры максимум типа
they make here, here they take a barrel like this and
делают вот у нас так берут бочку такую
it heats up on its own
она сама нагревается
Ay Masya
Ай Мася
This is
Это кошка
my cat in kind yes well damn that’s my Wow the vegetable
моя в натуре да ну блин Вот мо Ого
garden is cool And where is more So where is
огород прикольны А где боле Так а где
the shower  where is the shower room with the boiler now I'll
душевая где душевая с бойлером сейчас я
show you I mean it's not at home it's on the
тебе покажу В смысле она не дома она на
street Well of course it's not at home I'm
улице Ну конечно не дома я же тебе
telling you here before it's built
говорю у нас перед тем как строится
wait it turns out look You're taking it in the evening
подожди то получается смотри Ты вечером
shower and through the garden you go
принимаешь душ и через огород идёшь
home. You see like this and the shower
домой Вот видишь так а саму душевую
cabin itself Show what is it that there is a shower Bo I
кабину Покажи что это что там душ Бо я
see the boiler and down Down Show the shower
бойлер вижу а вниз Вниз Покажи душевую
cabin down the bathtub Show there is no shower
кабину вниз ванну Покажи нету душевой
cabin it’s just wooden Do And where
кабины это просто деревянный Ду А где
where Well where do you stand Show me the floor on
где Ну где ты встаёшь Покажи вот пол на
which you get up when you wash. And it’s
который ты встаёшь когда моешься А
just a wooden shower, like I understand that there’s a
просто деревянный душ типа понял то есть
leak down there through a tree. It’s absolutely
там через дерево утекает вниз Совершенно
true that there’s a hole under this
верно что под этим
tree, as I understand it  and your toilet is
деревом яма я так понимаю и туалет у
wooden Well, for now, yes, 2
деревянный Ну пока да 2
years in the sense Well, yes,
года в смысле Ну да то есть ты 2
that is, you are 2 years old. And what do you not have, that is, for 2 years you
года А что у тебя нет то есть ты 2 года
actually go to the euro hole and this
реально ходишь в евро дырку да такую в
wooden one Well, look, you were born
деревянную Ну так а гляди ты родился
like this and immediately go to the toilet Yes  no, I
такой и сразу в унитаз Да нет так я не
can’t understand, look, your dad, mom,
могу понять смотри тебе папа мама
gave you an apartment and you go to the toilet like that.
подарили квартиру и ты ходишь такой в
And what have you achieved, not not me? I
унитаз А ты сам чего добился не не я Я
can’t understand. Why have
не могу понять А почему ты за вот эти 2
n’t you made a soul in your home in these 2 years?
года не сделал у себя дома типа душу не
Well, at the dacha, I haven’t built a house yet,
та вот на даче так я ещё я ещё дом не
I have an apartment in Krasnoyarsk.
построил у меня квартира в Красноярске
So wait, you’re building a house and a bathhouse,
Так подожди то ты строишь и дом и баню
then you would have already built a house. What’s the problem with
то построил бы уже дом А в чём проблема
building a house? Why do I have an apartment
построить дом Почему у меня квартира
about an apartment? I’m talking and this is a
есть про квартиру Я говорю и вот это
house  in the World Cup, the problem is to take and quickly build a
домик в ЧМ проблема взять и построить
house; the Russians have first a
дом у русских сначала
bathhouse, then a house, and first a bathhouse, then a house,
баня потом дом а сначала баня потом дом
that is, first they live in a bathhouse, then they live at
то есть сначала живут в бане потом живут
home, and why do I live? I have a
дома да почему я живу Вот у меня
makeshift 6 ours, I understand. How much
времянка 6 наше понял А сколько ты тут
time do you spend here a
проводишь времени в
year?  in the summer only in the summer That is,
году только летом только летом То есть
you go to this wooden toilet every summer
ты ВС лето ходишь в этот деревянный
and it’s flies Well, in short,
туалет и это а мухи Вот это они ж короче
there they are, show you my toilet,
там тебе показать мой туалет
I still don’t believe that there’s really no such thing as a wooden one with
ещё я не верю что реально деревянный с
a hole,
дыркой такой
it’s there, like at home, a toilet in a
нет это там как у тебя дома унитаз в
wooden toilet, like a toilet seat.  no no
деревянном туалете Как стульчак нет нет
there's not a toilet there, yes you're driving it like a toilet seat
там не унитаз да ты гонишь как стульчак
- it's a chair chair in the toilet Do you know
- это стул стул в туалете Ты знаешь что
what a toilet seat is no no Neva I thought
такое стульчак нет нет Нева Я думал
a toilet seat is a small chair
стульчак - это маленький стульчик
toilet seat Well La Show me What year are you
стульчак Ну Ля Покажи Какого года ты
what year am I in eighty-one and
какого года я во восемьдесят первого а
eighty-one Well, how do you
восемьдесят первого Ну да вам откуда
know from mom and dad to ask what a
знать у папы с мамой спросить что такой
toilet seat is Well, I’m not I’m with you now in
стульчак Ну так я не я сейчас с тобой
common can you really show what a
общ можешь показать реально что такое
toilet seat is Well, you’re at mom and dad’s  Ask and
стульчак Ну ты у мамы с папой Спроси да
let’s do it normally. I’m not going to say
давай нормально Я же не буду говорить
damn it, tell me what a toilet seat is,
там блин скажите мне что такое стульчак
so ask. Maybe they’ll give me a slap on the head. Yes, it’s
так спроси Может подзатыльника дадут Да
real. Show me what you really have. You want to
реально Покажи реально у тебя Ты хочешь
say that you have a toilet  wooden but
сказать что у тебя туалет деревянный но
not just a hole on the floor not just a hole on the
не просто дырка полу не просто дырка на
cards sit but in silence Show us we
картах сидеть а а вот молча Покажи
really won’t see the toilet the
реально не увидим стульчак
flies came off this guy just made a promo How to
мух вот тип прямо сделал промо Как
advertise
прорекламировать
to Russia Yes, we really dream of
к России Да вот мы прям мечтаем чтобы
building this bathhouse like this too 2 years 2 years
тоже так строить эту баню 2 года 2 года
going to  wooden Yes, that’s just a dream,
ходить в деревянную Да вот прям мечта
in short, every Ukrainian we sit and
короче каждого украинца мы сидим и
watch and think. Moreover, now
смотрим и думаем Да больше того сейчас у
we have viewers from there USA there Britain
нас зрители есть из там США там Британии
Germany South Korea Baltic countries they are
Германии Южной Кореи стран балти они
now
сечас
they look, too, I want to go to Krasnoyarsk, I also want to
смотрят тоже хочу в Красноярск тоже хочу
build a dacha there. Yes, you’re all sitting there
там дачу строить Да вот сидите все
now, envying him. Yes, he
сейчас такие завидуйте ему Да у него
has a boiler with a shower; a wooden shower;
бойлер есть с душем душ деревянный
just the floor is stupid; the pieces of wood flow through
просто пол тупо деревяшки через
the pieces of wood
деревяшки
too.
тоже
Oh,
О
hello, good evening, I’m from the city of
здравствуйте Добрый вечер я из города
Khmelnitsky. Where are you from in Rostov? I
Хмельницкий Вы откуда Ростов
understand how you feel  to the fact that
понял как вы относитесь к тому что
Ukraine is carrying out drone strikes on the
Украина наносит удары дронами по
territory of the Russian
территории Российской
Federation Well, this is a war Well, that is, this is
Федерации Ну это же война Ну то есть это
how it was intended, it
так и задумано
was intended  who Well, to those who started a
было задумано кем Ну тем кто начал
special military operation Well, when
специальную военную операцию Ну когда
someone starts a war He probably
кто-то начинает войну Он наверно
understands that This is such a thing It howls as
понимает что Это такая вещь Она вою
sharp as a knife, it’s interesting that it
острая как нож у интересно то есть
turns out that Putin planned it That way, he
получается Путин так и планировал Да что
will do his own thing and as a result they will
он сделает сво и в результате будут
bomb the territory of Russia Yes I  I don’t know
бомбить территорию России Да я не знаю
what he was planning. I can’t get into his
что он планировал Я же не могу в его
head what he was planning there. Well,
голову залезть что он там планировал Ну
okay. And when it started, did you think
хорошо А когда началось сво вы вы думали
that it would happen like this, that it would bomb
что вот так будет что будет бомбить
the territory of the Russian Federation? Yes, I’m
территорию Российской Федерации Да я в
sure of that; it was interesting because
этом уверен был интересно потому что
many, Yes, many thought No.  A  like now
многие Да многие думали Нет а как сечас
Ukraine is being captured and that’s it. So you start
Украину захват и всё Вот вы начинаете
a fight in
драку на ули
someone’s street and hit him in the face, do you
кому-то к человеку и бьёте его в лицо вы
expect that he will come back to you or do
ожидаете что вам прилетит в ответку или
you think that this happens? People have
вы думаете что это бывает Люди бывают
such situations that the bully thinks that he is
такие ситуации что хулиган Думает что он
now going to give some kind of nerd  in the face and
сейчас какого-то Ботана даст в лицо и
he will run away Yes, but Botan turns out to be not
тот убежит Да а Ботан оказывается не
a nerd, but a type A normal kid
ботаном да типа А нормальным пацанчика
who trained, plus
который тренировался да плюс ещё выходят
his friends come out and say Listen, well, yes, that
его друзья да и говорят Слушай ну да то
is, he sometimes miscalculated Yes, well
есть он бывает не рассчитал Да ну
the situation is different Well, in general, theoretically, you should still mean that there will be an answer. This is understandable, and as if any normal person understands that maybe it’s well, in short, it’s understandable. Yes, it happens in different ways. It’s good. And then the question turns out that Well, now I’m thinking to you It’s already obvious Yes, that there will no longer be any capture of Kyiv at all, it’s true. Well, as I understand it, now we are talking about some regiments, insignificantly. Well, that is, all sorts of Federations. Yes, it boils down to the fact that there is a capture of some village. Well, in general- then yes  yes, then how do you
село Ну в общем-то да да то как вы
see the continuation of this war? Well,
видите тогда продолжение этой войны Ну
what should be a victory for the Russian Federation? Oh,
что для Российской Федерации должно быть
I don’t know what will happen there. Victory, you
победой О я не знаю что там будет Победа
know, maybe Victory can
это понимаете может Победа
appear. Yes, anything can happen.
объявиться Да всё что угодно может быть
Victory here is propaganda - this is such a thing,
Победа тут пропаганда - это ж такая вещь
it will justify anything, I understand  Do you
она всё что угодно оправдает понял у вас
have any question for me?
ко мне есть какой-то вопрос
Yes, I don’t know. Well, tell me, what about you in general?
Да не знаю Ну скажите а вы вообще Вот
Somehow you are thinking about the topic for yourself
как-то вы размышляете на тему для себя
Why did this happen to
Почему именно с нами это случилось с
us? Who did this happen to you? Well, with Ukraine So
вами это с кем Ну с Украиной Так
Wait, you from  Ukraine or from Russia from
Подождите вы из Украины или из России из
Russia And you mean or with us
рос А вы типа имеете в виду или с нами
Well, it’s clear Yes, why of course I know
Ну так понятно Да почему конечно знаю
Just like the Georgians reason
Так же само как грузины рассуждают
Why the Moldovans with them Why
Почему именно с ними молдаване Почему
with them Yes, the fact is that the
именно с ними Да дело в том что
Russian Federation Yes, this is an underdeveloped
Российская Федерация Да это недоразвитый
Imperial project  Yes, there was an era
се Имперский проект Да вот была Эпоха
when states were consolidated in the Empire, the
когда государства укрупнить в Империи
British Empire, the Ottoman Empire, the
там британская Империя Османская империя
Austro-Hungarian Russian Empire, as
австро-венгерская Российская империя в
a result of the First World War, part of
результате первой мировой войны часть
the empire ceased to exist.  the
империи прекратила своё существование
Ottoman Empire broke up into national
османское распалась на национальные
states Yes, the Austro-Hungarian
государства Да австро-венгерская
Russian Empire broke up into
Российская империя распалась на
national states Yes there is
национальные государства Да там
Finland Ukraine Poland And so on Yes the
Финляндия Украина Польша И так дальше Да
rest uh further Lenin through the
осталь вот ээ дальше Ленин путём
dictatorship Yes introduced on the remnants of the
диктатуры Да введённой на остатках
Russian Empire reassembled part of this
Российской империи пересобрал часть этой
Russian Empire under the name of the USSR
Российской империи под названием СССР
returned the
вернул
Caucasian countries there  Ukraine,
ээ кавказские страны туда Украину
Belarus, and then the Baltic countries captured it
Белорусь э потом захватили ещё страны
in the forties, already under Stalin,
балтии в сороковых годах уже при Сталине
and so on  In the ninety-first year, the
так вот дальше В девяносто первом году
second collapse of the Russian Empire took place,
произошёл второй распад Российской
that is, the Union Republics. Yes, they
империи да то есть союзные Республики Да
went into free navigation. And those
пошли в Свободное плавание А те
autonomous republics that were
автономные республики которые были в
part of the RSFSR raised their status to
составе РСФСР повысили свой статус до
national republics, that is, now
национальных республик да то есть сейчас
if we look at the Constitution of Yakutia, it
если мы смотрим Конституцию Якутии там
says article one, the republic of the Union of Artists is
написано статья один республика СХ есть
democratic
демократическое
we look at the state of the Republic of Tatarstan
государство смотрим Республика Татарстан
There is a state in all the constitutions of
Есть государство во всех конституциях
national republics it is written that the
национальных республиках пишется что
first article that they are states
первой статье что они есть государствами
and so the next stage will be the collapse  The
так вот и следующий этап будет распада
Russian Empire is the third separation of
Российской Империи это третий выделение
these national states into
этих национальных государств в
sovereign states Yes, the division of
суверенные государства Да разделение
Russia on a regional basis there
России по региональному принципу там
Some Far Eastern republic
Дальневосточная какая-то республика
will be Siberian And so on, yes, that is,
будет Сибирская И так дальше да то есть
there is an objective process of disintegration of the
идёт объективный процесс распада
Russian Empire, that’s
Российской Империи вот и
all in Russia there are reactionary forces
всё в России есть реакционные силы
that want to restore the
которые хотят восстановить там
Russian there  the empire there, they remember
Российскую империю там вот они там мнят
some kind of past greatness and now they want to
о былом величии каком-то и вот они хотят
restore it. Well, this is a historical
восстановить её Ну это уже исторический
process that cannot be
процесс не
stopped. I’m talking a little about something else, of course.
остановить Я немножко о другом конечно
Thank you for
Спасибо за
excursion but I was asking a little about something else
экскурс но я немножко о другом спрашивал
I was asking Ukraine here in Ukraine You are,
Я спрашивал Украина вот в Украине Вот вы
yes, you are from Ukraine I understand correctly
да вы же из Украины Правильно я понимаю
yes yes from
да да из
Ukraine you somehow thought why
Украины вы как-то думали почему именно с
this happened to us Why didn’t
нами это произошло Почему не с другими
this happen to other states But it happened to us
это государствами не произошло А с нами
I’m talking to Georgia, also not
произошло я же говорю с Грузией также не
me, about the same thing happened to Georgia too. Yes, I’ll
я с Грузией также произошло грузи
explain. Let’s explain. Why
самое Да объясняю Давайте разм Почему
did it happen to Estonia because Estonia
произошло с эстонией потому что Эстония
managed to join NATO? Why didn’t it happen
успела войти в НАТО Почему не произошло
to Latvia  Latvia managed to join NATO
с латвией Латвия успела войти в НАТО
Why didn’t it happen to Lithuania Lithuania
Почему не произошло с Литвой Литва
managed to join NATO Why didn’t it come from
успела войти в НАТО Почему не пришло с
Belarus because Belarus
Белоруссию потому что Белоруссию
was occupied in a different way Yes soft
оккупировали другим способом Да мягким
type yes why did it happen to Moldova
типа да почему ээ произошло с Молдовой
Yes because it did not have time to
Да потому что она не успела да
integrate into European structures
интегрироваться в европейские структуры
Yes and during the collapse  Russia made a union
Да и при развале Союза Россия сделала
There, during the Dniester, it happened with Georgia Yes,
Там при днестром произошло с Грузией Да
because it didn’t have time to join NATO And so
потому что не успела войти в НАТО И так
on Everything is
дальше Всё
fine Well, I see the root cause
хорошо Ну я вижу вот первопричину всё
anyway  not truncated not the root cause, just
равно не усек не первопричина как раз
look at the root cause - this is that in the
смотрите первопричина - это то что в
Russian Federation there is a great demand
Российской Федерации есть большой спрос
among even society for the restoration of
среди даже общества на восстановление
these territories within the framework of a single
вот этих территорий в рамках единого
state Russian Empire Soviet
государства Российская империя Советский
Union And so on Your second
Союз И так дальше Вторая ваша
mistake is your first mistake you are
ошибка вы первая ваша ошибка вы
placing the wrong emphasis on the
неправильно расставляет акценты о
reasons  happened Place
причинах произо Расставьте правильно
your accents correctly Place your accents Come on, the second
Расставьте свои акценты А ну Вторая
mistake is you
ошибка Вы
and you want to place yours Place yours
а расставить свои хотите вы Расставьте
Well, tell me What are yours here in your opinion
Ну скажите Какие ваши вот по-вашему
why with
почему именно с
us why with you Yes what are
нами почему именно с вами Да какие вы
your accents
ваши акценты
you ended up in  in an unnecessary place at an unnecessary
вы оказались в ненужном месте в ненужное
time, an argument, and instead of
время аргумент да и вместо того чтобы
behaving carefully when there is
себя вести аккуратно когда с вами рядом
a big heavy one next to you
большой тяжёлый
and Well, let you say so there, you can
и Ну пусть вы так говорите там можно
call it differently, or
по-другому это назвать как по-другому
call it differently Well, it doesn’t
это назвать Ну не
matter what you want, if it makes you feel
суть хотите как хотите если вам от этого
better  it will be possible So
легче будет можете Так
you, Well, okay, so instead of
вы вот Ну хорошо вот и вместо того чтобы
behaving carefully, you started to
вести себя аккуратно вы начали его
bully him And how it should have been Tell
задирать А как надо было Расскажите
Tell me an example At what point we
Расскажите пример В каком моменте мы
started leading I don’t want you I want an example
начали вести я не хочу Вас Я хочу пример
I want to understand Yes, I want to
Я хочу чтобы понять Да я хочу
figure it out, do an error analysis
разобраться сделать анализ ошибок работу
you know, I like to work on mistakes, this is
над ошибками знаете я люблю делать Вот в
where  where exactly did we behave
каком месте где конкретно мы повели себя
carelessly? I don’t want to
неаккуратно я я не хочу как бы вот в
enter into such a polemic with you. Yes, it’s not
такую полемику вступать с вами Да не
a polemic for me so that I understand, but you
полемика мне для себя чтобы я понял а вы
for yourself, you just twist it for yourself, I
для себя вы для себя просто покрутить
think it seems to me that we
мне каже Мне кажется что неаккуратно мы
acted carelessly on August 24,
поступили 24 этого августа девяносто
1991  the year that Independence was proclaimed
первого года что провозгласили
and since then Yes, Russia
Независимость и с тех пор Да вот Россия
believes that we had this sloppy movement
считает что это неаккуратное движение
Uh-huh Well, where exactly Well, in what year did
нас Угу Ну где конкретно Ну в каком году
we enter
мы поступили
sloppy I want to understand, I’m not arguing,
неаккуратно Я хочу понять я же не спорю
I want to
я хочу
understand You are a reasonable person, you thought
понять Вы разумный вы человек вы подумал
you I can’t I can’t understand what
вы Я не могу не могу понять какой именно
year you are looking at from deno pergo so many years
год смотрите с дено перго столько лет
have passed and I can understand exactly where we
прошло и могу понять где мы именно
acted sloppyly in what year and
неаккуратно поступили в каком году да
there were little things  everything Well, where is it And
там было по мелочам всё Ну да где вот А
in what year did it become like this, not in detail,
в каком году уже так стало не по мелочам
but precisely sloppy, in
а именно неаккуратно всё по
detail everything is absolutely honest to tell me
мелочам абсолютно честно сказать мне
in general there is no way to Ukraine at all Yes, I understand
вообще до Украины вообще нет Да я понял
Well, tell me so that I can understand, here you tell me  The
Ну скажите мне чтобы я понял вот вы мне
Ukrainian's eyes were really opened, I now
украинцу открыли реально глаза я теперь
realized that somewhere we somewhere we
понял что где-то мы где-то мы не так
behaved wrong, here are examples, you can tell
себя повели вот примеры можете сказать
examples where we behaved carelessly,
примеры где мы себя неаккуратно повели
let me not, don't let you,
давайте я не буду Не давайте вы будете
let's see it, it's your mistake, what are you
Давайте это видите ваша ошибка что вы
saying, pile on And you  there are no examples
говорите навалите И у вас нету примеров
Well, I’ll tell you this, the smart one
Ну я вам так скажу умный
will understand, let’s try you, like the
поймёт давайте вы попробуйте вы как
smart one, he’ll
умный умней
explain it smarter, you know, he’ll never be able to
объяснит знаете го никогда не сможет
explain But the smart one can, I believe that
объяснить А умный сможет вот я верю что
you are very smart,
вы умны совсем пожи
I’m very emotional myself  I’m such a
Я очень эмоциональны я Сам по себе такой
person myself and I’ll tell you more I’ve had
человек и я вам больше скажу у меня 2
some kind of increased emotional
года как-то повышенная эмоциональная
sensitivity for 2 years I don’t know why this is so I
чувствительность Я не знаю почему так Я
just want to get to the bottom of the reason where we
просто хочу докопаться до причины где мы
acted carelessly so that later we don’t make
неаккуратно повели чтобы потом не делать
such mistakes I will preach to people
таких ошибок Я буду проповедовать людям
that we have to do it carefully
что мы должны это будет аккуратно
centrism is called a current, you understand I
центризм называться течение понимаете Я
will say that we should be
буду говорить что мы должны быть
focused on careful behavior
сконцентрированы на аккуратном поведение
towards a
к
neighbor, you can. Well, if you are
соседу можете Ну если вам а
insulting someone, you feel
Вот оскорбляя кого-то вы чувствуете себя
better than nobles. This is your right, yes,
лучше выше благород Это Ваше право да да
here I am, for example, look, I’m honest  I say,
Вот я например смотри Я честно говорю
look, when I voice it, for example,
смотрите Я когда вот например озвучиваю
I say Putin somehow doesn’t change the
говорю Путин как-то не меняет от этого
overall situation, but I’m somehow more
общую ситуацию но мне как-то более
inspired and I’m, uh, let’s say, your
воодушевленно и у меня ээ скажем Ваше
right, yes, yes, look, my
право да да смотрите у меня начинает
efficiency is starting to improve, I get more
работоспособность повышаться я больше
things done per day, in general, it’s super, yes it’s
дел делаю в день Вообще супер да это
good This is probably good for you
хорошо Это хорошо наверное для вас
for others whose
для других чей
Crimea is legally Ukraine, but in fact
Крым юридически он Украины А фактически
Russia That is, it is occupied by the Russian
России То есть он оккупирован Российской
Federation Yes, it is actually Russian,
Федерацией Да он фактически российский
that is, it is occupied, understood
то есть оккупирован понял
yes Or is there something wrong with  Do you have a question for me
да Или что-то не так есть у вас ко мне
or what kind of question?
вопрос или там ну какие Вопрос как
Look, if my legal phone number is mine and they
смотри если юридический телефон мой а
took it You, that’s
забрали его Вы то это ж
theft No, that’s Well, I understand
воровство Не ну это Ну то всё я понял
everything That’s right, I agree with you on Crimea
Всё правильно я согласен с вами по Крыму
Yes, okay, you have a question for me
окей у вас ко мне какой-то вопрос есть
more Yes, it’s useless to ask you a question
ещё Да это бесполезно ва вопрос задавать
Well, that’s it, let’s go, I’ve established myself, I’ll move
Ну всё Давайте Я само утвердился пойду
on, come on, subscribe to us on Instagram, I
дальше Давай подпишись на ми Instagram Я
don’t know why, why should you
не знаю для чого це тоб для чого ще тоб
marvel at everything?  th face Ale for you
там дивитись на оцей й фейс Але для тебе
tse about two [ __ ] ri clicks And you trim me and
це о два або ри клика А ты тримае мене и
I will be KTA in me there bathed
я буду КТА в мене там купало
and in me there will be a cool setup to work robiti
и в мене буде класный настр щоб робити
but cool video message on th Instagram Popik
но крут вдео пись на й Instagram Попик
Andriy
Андрий вот
like this, let me
так давай я тебя
check for you N
чекаю N